Jon Reid

10 Adam Christie Avenue Hillside Montrose DD10 9GE

jdreid5@aol.com +44 (0) 7479 532684 Hard-working, confident individual currently completing a software development bootcamp focused on full-stack engineering. Works well within a team and thrives in a culture of collaboration. Possesses a broad academic education and strong work ethic which is evident in my work experience. Thoroughly passionate about all things tech and looking to take my next step in my career into the world of software development.

Bootcamp Experience

Full-stack software engineering course through ITCareerSwitch, with training provided by Codecademy Pro. Front-end portion heavily focused on JavaScript, including the React/Redux stack. Developed a Redditclone web app that retrieved information from the Reddit JSON API to display posts and comments in real time. Project was version controlled using Git and GitHub, and deployed upon completion via Netlify with a CI/CD pipeline for further development.

The site is available to view at https://jdreid5-reddit-minimal.netlify.app, with the repository available at https://github.com/jdreid5/reddit-minimal.

Backend portion covered JavaScript in the node.js runtime, Express.js as a server-side framework, and PostgreSQL. Backend culminated in producing an e-commerce RESTful API to deliver CRUD operations such as registering an account and placing an order.

Work Experience

January 2023 - July 2023

Retail Stocktaker & Driver - Retail & Asset Solutions Ltd

Position encompassed two main roles – minibus driver & stocktaker. As a driver, punctuality between destinations was crucial in my role to maintain the operational efficiency of the organisation.

As a stocktaker, role demanded constant focus and attention to detail, as well as the ability to perform effectively during long shifts, in order to ensure the integrity of inventory records for the clients that Retail & Asset Solutions Ltd served, including Tesco, Primark & BP.

2012 - 2018, 2019 - 2022

Farm Worker/Agricultural Contractor — J. D. Reid & Partners

Role developed as experience grew, starting as part-time farm worker to full time agricultural contractor, carrying out a range of duties across the year.

Highly disciplined, independent work ethic required in order to work extended shifts during time sensitive periods throughout the year.

January 2019 - September 2019

Customer Service Advisor, Retail Banking - Santander UK

Customer service representative carrying out telephone banking for the retail sector.

Rapid development of problem-solving skills through dealing with complex customer queries.

Excellent interpersonal skills required to deliver a positive customer experience in challenging situations.

June 2018 - December 2018

Bar Team Member - Missoula, Glasgow

Full time work in an extremely busy city centre cocktail bar with extended opening hours to 3am during the weekend.

High pressure environment requiring ability to stay calm under duress whilst multi-tasking efficiently within a team.

Key responsibilities:

- Plan driving routes & coordinate pickups with stocktaking staff
- Ensure safe transportation of staff to designated locations
- Conduct precise counts of store products

Key responsibilities:

- Supervising a team of up to 8 people
- Machinery operation & maintenance
- Stock control to maintain an efficient operational workflow
- Manual labouring for extended hours in all weather

Key responsibilities:

- Telephone banking & account openings/closures
- Security authentication with customers, adhering to strict protocols
- Updating customer information in accordance with GDPR requirements

Key responsibilities:

- Opening and closing the bar
- Stock control
- Bartending and table service

Technical Experience

- HTML & CSS
- JavaScript
- React
- Redux
- PHPPython
- Git
- Node.js
- Express.js

Skills

- Committed to self-improvement
- Confident communicator
- Experienced remote worker
- Meticulous attention to detail
- Tenacious in approach to work

Education

2020 - 2022

University of the Highlands & Islands BSc Audio Engineering with Distinction

2016 – 2017 University of Strathclyde MSc Sustainable Engineering: Offshore Renewable Energy with Merit

2012 – 2016 University of Strathclyde 2:1 BEng (Hons) Sports Design Engineering

2006 – 2012 Mearns Academy, Laurencekirk

References available on request.